- PREVIOUSLY ON HAVEN...
- YOU'VE BEEN FALSIFYING
POLICE REPORTS.
- I'VE BEEN DOING WHAT
WE'VE ALWAYS DONE IN HAVEN.
- WE'RE GONNA BE LOOKING
FOR A NEW CHIEF IMMEDIATELY.
- SOMEONE WANTS ME OUT?
IT'S THE REV, ISN'T IT?
- HE WANTS TO BE CHIEF?
- HE WANTS TO CONTROL
WHOEVER IS.
- YOU ARE AMAZING.
I WANT YOU, AUDREY,
BECAUSE YOU'RE YOU.
- THIS IS EVI.
- I'M DUKE'S WIFE.
WHY ARE YOU EVEN HERE?
- IT'S MY DAD.
THE OLD BASTARD
MADE ME SWEAR
THAT I WOULD COME BACK HERE
IF THE TROUBLES EVER RETURNED.
AND THEN HE DIED.
- DUKE DOESN'T SUSPECT ANYTHING?
- NO.
AND NOW THAT HE KNOWS
HIS FATHER WAS MURDERED,
YOU'VE GOT HIM.
- [chuckles]
- HI, CATHY.
HOW'S YOUR LITTLE MAN TODAY?
GOOD TO SEE YA, MARTHA.
- NOT THE FIRST TIME
WE'VE CAUGHT YOU
BREAKING AND ENTERING, DWIGHT.
- CAUGHT ME?
CHIEF WUORNOS
CAN CLEAR THIS UP.
- YOU HAVEN'T HEARD.
WUORNOS ISN'T CHIEF ANYMORE.
WE GOT A NEW GUY.
SO NO MORE
SPECIAL TREATMENT FOR...
SPECIAL PEOPLE,
YOU KNOW?
- ARE YOU SWEATIN'?
- IT'S WARM OUT HERE.
- I WOULDN'T SAY THAT.
- DWIGHT.
WHAT'S THIS?
- DID A LITTLE CLEANUP AT
THE CENTRAL COAST MEAT PACKING.
- WITH A CROSSBOW?
I GOT THIS
FROM NOW, PAUL.
- FINE.
- PAUL.
CUFFS.
- SO THERE'S A NEW CHIEF?
- YEAH. THE SELECTMAN
SENT IN THIS GUY MERRILL.
HE'S A REFORMER
FROM BRUNSWICK,
AND I THINK HE'S CLUELESS
ABOUT THE TROUBLES.
- WON'T BE FOR LONG.
- SPRINKLES?
- OH, YEAH.
- JUST WATCH
WHERE YOU POINT THIS THING.
- WHAT DID I CATCH
IN THAT PLACE?
WHAT THE HELL?
[thud]
- ALL RIGHT,
SO YOU'RE OKAY
WITH TAKING
THE GRAVEYARD SHIFT TONIGHT?
- MM-HMM. IT'S GONNA BE GOOD.
I'M NOT IN CHARGE.
AND MOST OF HAVEN'S UP
AT THE BOAT PARADE, SO GO.
GO ON YOUR--
YOUR DATE.
- IT'S NOT A DATE.
- OH, SURE.
OF COURSE. THAT'S WHY
I'VE NEVER SEEN YOU SO NERVOUS.
BECAUSE OF YOUR NON-DATE.
- IT'S JUST--IT'S BEEN--
IT'S BEEN, WHAT, A MONTH
SINCE CHRIS LEFT FOR LONDON,
AND HIS TROUBLE WAS STILL,
YOU KNOW, RELATIVELY NEW.
- RIGHT,
AND PEOPLE SEE CHRIS
AND THEN THEY'RE
IMMEDIATELY VERY...
FOND OF HIM.
IT'S NOTHING
TO WORRY ABOUT.
- NO?
- NO.
- [chuckles]
NO.
- GOT A VISITOR
UP FRONT, HON'.
- THANKS.
- FOR NATHAN. CROCKER'S HERE.
- YOU KNOW THAT I HATE
THAT YOU'RE A COP, RIGHT?
- YEAH.
AND THAT I THINK
IT'S RIDICULOUS
THAT THEY PUT YOU
IN CHARGE OF THIS PLACE.
- UH-HUH.
- BUT FOR CERTAIN REASONS...
IT MAKES SENSE.
- WELL, I'M NOT THE CHIEF
ANYMORE, YOU REMEMBER?
- YEAH.
BUT DO YOU WANNA KNOW WHY
YOU'RE NOT THE CHIEF ANYMORE?
EVI.
SHE TIPPED OFF THE REV
ABOUT YOUR FILE
ON THE TROUBLED PEOPLE.
I SAW IT
ON HER PHONE.
- I KNEW
IT WAS THE REV.
BUT HOW THE HELL
IS EVI INVOLVED?
- YOU GOT ME.
I MEAN, THINK HOW I FEEL.
I'M MARRIED TO HER.
GOD ONLY KNOWS WHAT ELSE
SHE'S HIDING.
LOOK...
I FIGURE WE DO THIS HERE.
OTHERWISE SHE'D BOLT.
I TOLD HER
THAT YOU WERE HELPING ME
WITH MY PARKING TICKETS.
IT WAS THE BEST
I COULD COME UP WITH.
- HMM. OKAY.
LET'S PUT HER
IN THE BREAK ROOM.
- UM...
WHAT THE HELL IS THAT?
- DID DUKE FINALLY PAY
HIS PARKING TICKETS?
MM. OH...
CHRIS.
- OH, RIGHT.
WORKPLACE.
- YEAH.
- I GUESS
I JUST DON'T CARE.
- OKAY, HEY, HEY, HEY.
- WHAT?
- WHY DON'T I
JUST GRAB MY STUFF,
AND THEN WE CAN GO
TO THE PARADE?
- PARADE?
WITH BOATS, AND LIGHTS,
AND DRINKING, AND PEOPLE?
- YEAH.
- NO.
I DON'T WANNA SEE
ANYONE BUT YOU.
- PARKER, YOU'D BETTER
GET OUT HERE.
- I GOTTA...
- NO, NO,
WE GOT PLANS.
THIS BETTER NOT
BE IMPORTANT.
[sighs]
I LOVE THAT YOU
DON'T LISTEN TO ME!
- IS THAT BLACK BLOOD?
THAT'S OFFICER STARK.
- HE'S DEAD.
[folk music]
&l &l
- I JUST SAW HIM.
HE LOOKED PALE
AND SWEATY, BUT NOT--
- NOT AS DEAD?
'CAUSE...
HE'S PRETTY DEAD.
- LOOK, HIS VEINS ARE--
THEY'RE BLACK.
- WHAT THE HELL
IS THIS?
IS THAT ONE
OF MY OFFICERS?
- THAT'S CHIEF MERRILL.
- AND WHO ARE YOU?
- I AM...
NOBODY.
- WHAT DO YOU THINK
COULD CAUSE SOMETHING LIKE THIS?
- [sighs]
- MAYBE A CHEMICAL WEAPON.
- WE'RE NOT A TARGET
FOR ANYTHING LIKE THAT.
- WE MAY WANNA CONSIDER
OTHER POSSIBILITIES.
- ARE YOU SAYING THIS TOWN
DOESN'T HAVE ANY LOCAL FANATICS?
GROUPS WITH A REASON TO TARGET
THE HAVEN POLICE DEPARTMENT?
I SUGGEST YOU LOOK
INTO THAT RIGHT NOW.
[indistinct chattering]
- THIS ISN'T THE PENTAGON.
WHO'S GONNA STAGE
A CHEMICAL ATTACK IN HAVEN?
- THE MORE PEOPLE KNOW
ABOUT THE TROUBLED,
- DO YOU THINK THE REV
IS WHIPPING THEM UP?
- DUKE JUST TOLD ME
THAT THE REV GOT ME FIRED.
- ARE YOU KIDDING ME?
- I KNEW HE'D TRY
AND GET ME OUT EVENTUALLY.
IT JUST HAPPENED SOONER
THAN I EXPECTED.
- ALL RIGHT,
SO THE REV GETS HIS CHIEF.
WHY ATTACK
THE DEPARTMENT NOW?
- UNLESS THE PERP IS SOMEONE
UNHAPPY ABOUT MERRILL.
- YOU GET REPLACED.
YOU DO HAVE YOUR FANS.
- YOU THINK
IT'S SOMEONE PRO-TROUBLED
WITH TECHNICAL KNOWHOW,
ACCESS TO CHEMICALS...
THE LAST PERSON
PAUL ARRESTED WAS DWIGHT.
- YEAH,
YOUR DAD'S CLEANER.
WE REALLY DON'T KNOW
THAT MUCH ABOUT HIM.
- HE'S DEAD?
- MAYBE YOU HAD A GRUDGE.
- NATHAN, LISTEN, I DIDN'T
DO ANYTHING TO THAT GUY, OKAY?
YOU REALLY NEED
TO START TRUSTING ME.
WITH THE NEW CHIEF
IN TOWN,
YOU MIGHT NEED ME
MORE THAN EVER.
[sighs]
- WE'RE GONNA DO THIS NOW?
- WAIT.
EVI.
SHOW HIM
WHAT YOU SHOWED ME.
- IT STARTS AT
THE EXTREMITIES.
- WE GOTTA GET HER
TO THE HOSPITAL.
- HOW LONG HAS SHE
BEEN LIKE THIS?
- EXCUSE ME.
SHE'S STANDING RIGHT HERE.
- DUKE,
WHAT'S HAPPENING?
- WERE YOU AND PARKER ABLE
TO LOCATE THE CHEMICAL SOURCE?
- NO, NOT YET, SIR.
- DID YOU HAVE
ANY DIRECT CONTACT
WITH OFFICER STARK?
SHAKE HIS HAND,
SIT AT HIS DESK, ANYTHING?
- NO.
- BUT THIS THING
KEEPS SPREADING.
SO IT'S GOTTA BE BIOLOGICAL
AND AIRBORNE.
- SIR.
- MA'AM, I'LL NEED YOU BACK
IN THE BREAK ROOM RIGHT NOW.
- WAIT A MINUTE, CHIEF.
- NOW!
LADIES AND GENTLEMEN,
WE MAY HAVE A BIOLOGICAL AGENT
IN THE BUILDING,
WHICH MEANS
WE FOLLOW PROCEDURE.
WE CANNOT ALLOW
THE CONTAMINATION
TO SPREAD FURTHER.
SO UNTIL THIS SITUATION
IS RESOLVED, NOBODY--
AND I MEAN NOBODY--
GOES IN OR OUT
OF THIS BUILDING.
THE HAVEN POLICE STATION
IS NOW UNDER QUARANTINE.
THIS IS A LOCKDOWN.
[dramatic music]
&l &l
- THIS THING IS CONTAINED.
ABSOLUTELY.
NO ONE'S LEAVING THE BUILDING
UNTIL IT'S CLEAR.
I'LL DO WHATEVER
HAS TO BE DONE.
COPY THAT.
I'LL AWAIT
FURTHER INSTRUCTION.
- WHAT DO THE STATE POLICE
HAVE TO SAY?
- THAT WE'RE DOING
THE RIGHT THING.
THE CONTAGION HASN'T SPREAD
BEYOND THE POLICE STATION.
- ALL RIGHT.
LIKE YOU ASKED, IT'S A LIST
OF EVERYONE IN THE STATION.
IT'S A SMALL GROUP.
- HUGH UNDERWOOD--
HE'S A DOCTOR?
- HE SAID HE'D LOOK AT THE BODY,
CHECK ON THE SICK.
- GOOD.
HAVE THE OFFICERS
KEEP AN EYE ON EVERYBODY.
- SIR, THE PEOPLE OUT THERE
ARE SCARED FOR THEIR LIVES.
- WELL, THAT'S
TO BE EXPECTED.
THAT'S WHY WE HAVE
TO MAINTAIN ORDER.
I PUT LOCK CODES
ON ALL THE DOORS.
ALL THE LANDLINES
ARE SHUT DOWN.
I WANT YOU TO CONFISCATE
EVERYBODY'S CELL PHONE.
- PEOPLE WILL WANNA STAY
IN TOUCH WITH THEIR FAMILIES.
- AND I'LL NEED YOU
AND THE REST OF THE DEPARTMENT
TO SURRENDER YOUR WEAPONS.
- WHAT?
- THEY'LL BE PLACED IN A LOCKER
UNDER MY OWN
PERSONAL ACCESS CODE.
WE CAN'T AFFORD
SOMEONE PANICKING,
DOING SOMETHING RASH.
THIS ISN'T OPTIONAL.
- WE CAN LEAVE ANYTIME.
I'LL JUST USE
MY IRRESISTIBLE CHARM
ON YOUR NEW BOSS.
- IT'S RESISTIBLE.
- WHAT ARE YOU DOING?
- JUST A LITTLE INSURANCE
IN CASE, YOU KNOW,
MERRILL STARTS
SEARCHING THE OFFICES.
I WANNA MAKE SURE I CAN FIND
AT LEAST ONE GUN.
- PARKER, YOU CALLED?
- YEAH.
STAN, YOU
AND THE DESK SARGE,
YOU'RE THE ONLY ONE WITH ACCESS
TO THE EVIDENCE ROOM, RIGHT?
- RIGHT.
- BOOK THIS IN EVIDENCE
AND KEEP IT THAT WAY.
- YOU GOT IT.
- CAN YOU TELL
WHAT'S HAPPENED TO HIM?
- WELL, IT'S STRANGE--
THIS, UM, DARK BLOOD.
I KNOW WHAT YOUR CHIEF SAID,
BUT CHEMICAL WEAPONS,
THEY DON'T ACT LIKE THIS.
- DO YOU THINK IT'S A VIRUS?
- NO.
NO, VIRUSES DON'T MOVE
WITH THIS KIND OF SPEED.
IT'S NOT LIKE ANY POISON
I'VE EVER SEEN.
IT'S LIKE NOTHING
IN THE KNOWN MEDICAL RECORD.
- ALL RIGHT. THANK YOU,
DR. UNDERWOOD.
- HEY, CALL ME HUGH.
- I DON'T THINK HAVEN'S
IN THE KNOWN MEDICAL RECORD.
- IT'S GOTTA BE
THE TROUBLES.
- SO WHOSE AFFLICTION
IS SPREADING THIS DISEASE?
- THE PERSON IS PROBABLY
STILL IN THE STATION.
THEY COULD BE INFECTING WHOEVER
THEY'RE COMING IN CONTACT WITH.
- OKAY, SO THIS HAPPENED,
WHAT, ABOUT 45 MINUTES AGO,
AND WE'VE ALREADY GOT
A NEW CASE?
THAT MEANS THAT ALL OF US
COULD BE SICK
WITHIN A MATTER OF HOURS.
I'M GONNA GO AHEAD
AND CHECK ON EVI.
- DWIGHT, IT'S NATHAN.
DO YOU READ?
- WOW.
OUTSIDE CONTACT.
I'M GONNA TELL
THE NEW CHIEF ON YOU.
- DWIGHT.
- IT'S ABOUT TIME.
WHAT THE HELL'S
GOING ON UP THERE?
- WE GOT SOME KIND
OF OUTBREAK HERE.
- MY BUDDY FROM
THE STATE POLICE CALLED.
SAID THEY GOT A TIPOFF.
ANY CALL FROM HAVEN
IS A PRANK.
C.D.C. GOT
THE SAME WARNING.
I FIGURED THERE WERE SOMETHING
YOU WERE TRYING TO KEEP QUIET.
- NO, I GUESS SOMEBODY IS.
WE'RE CUT OFF COMPLETELY.
- THINK SOMEONE
PLANNED THIS?
- I DON'T KNOW. JUST STAY
BY THE RADIO RIGHT NOW.
YOU'RE MY ONLY BACKUP.
- ROGER THAT.
- HEY. I CHECKED ON EVI.
SHE'S GETTING WORSE.
AND NOW THIS OTHER WOMAN'S
GOT IT TOO.
- SOMEBODY CALLED OFF
THE STATE POLICE AND THE C.D.C.
- WHAT? WHY?
- I'M MORE INTERESTED
IN WHO WANTS US CUT OFF.
- DO YOU THINK
THAT MERRILL'S TROUBLED?
- YOU DON'T THINK THE REV WOULD
VET HIS NEW PICK FOR CHIEF?
- OKAY, LOOK, IT'S NOT LIKE
THERE'S A TEST, ALL RIGHT?
MAYBE HE'S ISOLATING US
TO COVER HIS TRACKS.
- WE GOTTA BE SMART,
TRY AND REASON WITH HIM FIRST.
- ANY PERSON
LEAVING THIS BUILDING
WILL BE SHOT ON SIGHT.
- SHOT? BY WHO?
- THIS IS AN OUTBREAK.
IT NEEDS TO BE CONTAINED.
THERE ARE ARMED MEN
OUTSIDE THIS BUILDING
WHO WILL SHOOT ANYONE
SEEN LEAVING,
AND THEY WILL ONLY STAND DOWN
ON MY ORDER.
- WHO THE HELL ARE YOU?
- I'M THE GUY BRINGING
THIS PLACE UNDER CONTROL.
- OKAY, SIR,
HAVE YOU EVER CONSIDERED
THE POSSIBILITY
THAT MAYBE YOU'RE
THE ONE CAUSING THIS?
- YOU THINK
I'M TROUBLED?
THE TROUBLED
ARE WHY I'M HERE.
PEOPLE ARE SICK AND TIRED OF
A TOWN THAT LOOKS THE OTHER WAY
WHILE THE TROUBLED
BREAK THE LAW.
- THE REV BROUGHT YOU HERE,
DIDN'T HE?
- I'M HERE
TO ENFORCE THE LAW...
- OH, MY GOD.
CHIEF.
- TO TREAT THE TROUBLED
FOR WHAT THEY ARE--
CRIMINALS!
WE HAVE
TO MAINTAIN ORDER.
TO CONTAIN THIS.
NO ONE IS
LEAVING HERE UNTIL...
[coughs]
OH, DAMN IT.
YOUR KIND WON'T WIN.
[thud]
- FOR NOW JUST GO AHEAD
AND PUT HIM IN THE BATHROOM
WITH PAUL.
- MERRILL'S CELL PHONE.
IT'S PASSWORD-PROTECTED,
OF COURSE.
BUT HE MUST'VE KNOWN
HE WAS INFECTED THIS WHOLE TIME.
MAYBE HE REALLY DID
WANNA CONTAIN THE OUTBREAK.
- OR HE WAS TERRIFIED BY
WHOEVER WAS GIVING HIM ORDERS.
- DWIGHT, DO YOU SEE
ANYBODY OUT THERE?
- AFFIRMATIVE.
I'M NOT THE ONLY ONE
WATCHING THE STATION.
YOU GOT TWO ARMED WITH HANDGUNS
ON THE PERIMETER,
AT LEAST ONE ON THE ROOFTOP
OF THE POST OFFICE
ACROSS THE STREET,
PACKING A SNIPER RIFLE.
- HEAD OVER TO
THE SHERIFF'S DEPARTMENT
AND SEE IF YOU
CAN GET US SOME BACKUP.
- WILL DO.
- GOT MERRILL'S
ACCESS CARD.
WE CAN OVERRIDE
THE ELECTRONIC LOCKS.
WE CAN GET OUT
OF HERE.
- OF COURSE
WE CAN'T REALLY USE IT.
I MEAN, EVEN IF THESE GUYS
OUTSIDE ARE JUST FOR SHOW,
WE CAN'T LET
THIS THING OUT.
IT COULD WIPE OUT
ALL OF HAVEN.
- OKAY, IT LOOKS LIKE
THAT THIS THING KILLS PEOPLE
IN A FEW HOURS,
SO WE REALLY DON'T HAVE
THAT MUCH TIME.
I'M PROBABLY IMMUNE.
I'M JUST GONNA START
INTERVIEWING PEOPLE ONE BY ONE.
- EXCEPT EVI.
SHE'S MINE.
- I NEED TO GET
TO A HOSPITAL.
- WE CAN'T RISK
LETTING YOU OUT THERE.
WE DON'T KNOW
IF YOU'RE CONTAGIOUS.
WHOA, WHOA.
EVI.
THAT'S NOT THE ONLY REASON
WHY I'M HERE.
I NEED TO KNOW
WHY YOU SOLD ME OUT
TO THE SELECTMEN,
GOT ME FIRED AS CHIEF.
WHY ARE YOU WORKING
WITH THE REV?
- HOW'D YOU FIND OUT?
- DUKE.
HE SAW YOUR TEXT MESSAGE.
- THAT'S WHY HE'S BEEN
ACTING SO STRANGE.
LOOK,
THIS WASN'T PERSONAL.
I--I GOT IN TOO DEEP.
AND THAT'S WHEN THEY ASKED ME
TO DO THAT THING
WITH YOUR FILES.
- WHO'S "THEY"?
THE REV?
- HE'S ONE OF THEM.
- WHY IS IT SO IMPORTANT
TO HAVE ME OUT OF THE WAY?
- BECAUSE THEY SAID IT
WOULD BE HELPING DUKE.
- EXPLAIN IT TO ME.
- I CAN'T.
- THEN EXPLAIN IT
TO ME.
- I'M SORRY.
THESE MEN,
THEY SAID THAT
I'D BE HELPING YOU.
- HOW DOES GETTING NATHAN FIRED
POSSIBLY HELP ME?
- I--I DON'T KNOW,
OKAY?
THEY SAID THAT YOU
WERE IMPORTANT,
AND THAT YOU NEEDED
TO LEARN CERTAIN THINGS,
AND NATHAN NEEDED TO BE
OUT OF THE WAY
BECAUSE IT'D BE
A PROBLEM FOR YOU.
- [sighs]
HOW NAIVE ARE YOU?
OR DID THEY JUST PAY YOU
A LOT OF MONEY?
- OH, MY GOD.
IT'S NOT ABOUT THE MONEY.
I BELIEVED THEM, OKAY?
I BELIEVED THEM BECAUSE
THEY TOLD ME SOMETHING
THAT I ALWAYS KNEW.
YOU'RE SPECIAL.
- MM-HMM.
AND WHAT MAKES ME
SO SPECIAL?
- ALL I KNOW
IS THAT WHATEVER'S GOING ON
IN THIS TOWN,
THEY THINK THAT YOU'RE
IN THE MIDDLE OF IT.
- WHAT? TELL ME!
TELL ME!
- I CAN'T! I'M TELLING YOU
WHAT I KNOW!
- AFTER EVERYTHING,
YOU OWE ME SOME REAL ANSWERS.
- [sighs]
- SO WHAT?
EVERYTHING THAT'S
HAPPENED BETWEEN US
WAS CONTROLLED
BY THEM.
- NO. NO.
- YOU COULD DIE.
WE ALL COULD DIE.
THERE ARE MEN
OUT THERE WITH GUNS,
STOPPING US
FROM LEAVING.
EVEN WITH ALL THAT...
YOU STILL CAN'T
TELL ME THE TRUTH.
[door slams shut]
- [sniffles]
[gasps]
- UH, NIKKI COLEMAN.
I CAME IN TO FILE A, UH,
BUILDING PERMIT FOR MY BOSS.
- OKAY, GREAT.
AND DID YOU TALK TO, UH,
CHIEF MERRILL
OR OFFICER STARK?
- I TALKED WITH EVERYONE.
THEY KEPT TELLING ME
TO FILL OUT MORE FORMS.
DOES THIS MEAN
WE CAN GO NOW?
- YEAH, SOON.
UM, CAN YOU JUST GO AHEAD
AND SEND IN THE NEXT PERSON?
- YEAH.
- [sighs]
THIS IS RIDICULOUS.
DO WE REALLY
HAVE TO DO THIS?
- WELL, YOU KNOW
I CAN'T MAKE IT LOOK LIKE
YOU'RE GETTING
SPECIAL TREATMENT.
- FINE. I'LL MAKE IT
EASY FOR YA.
IT'S NOT ME.
NOW CAN I GO?
I'VE GOT A KILLER GAME
OF SOLITAIRE GOING.
IT'S THE ONLY CARD GAME
WHERE NOBODY LETS ME WIN.
- HAVE YOU SEEN EVI?
SHE'S MISSING. DUKE'S WORRIED.
- WELL, SHE CAN'T
BE THAT FAR.
- THE KEYCARD'S GONE.
EVI MUST HAVE IT.
[scanner beeps]
- WHERE ARE YOU?
- EVI.
- I KNOW YOU'RE OUT HERE!
COME ON!
- EVI, STOP!
PLEASE, JUST COME
BACK INSIDE.
- NO. I GOT OUT
FOR YOU.
I COULD RUN, BUT I'M
NOT GONNA RUN ANYMORE.
IF YOU WANT ANSWERS,
I'LL GET YOU YOUR ANSWERS.
- EVI!
[scanner beeps]
- GO BACK TO THE BUILDING.
- NO!
YOU'RE GONNA TELL HIM
WHAT HE WANTS TO KNOW--
[gunshot]
- EVI!
[rifle cocks]
- HOLD YOUR FIRE!
NOT HIM!
- YOU'RE GONNA BE
ALL RIGHT.
- OH, GOD.
I'M GONNA GO
GET SOME HELP.
- [breathes heavily]
WHY DID YOU DO THAT?
- I'M SO SORRY.
- HANG ON.
HELP'S ON THE WAY.
- [breathing heavily]
- NO, NO. NO, DUKE.
NOT LIKE THIS.
- IF YOU WERE EVER
MY FRIEND--
- YOU CAN'T JUST RUN OUT THERE!
BE SMARTER THAN THAT.
- NATHAN, GET THE HELL
OUT OF MY WAY!
- DUKE!
- AUDREY, YOU--
- NATHAN!
- I JUST SAVED HIS LIFE.
- ALL RIGHT, WELL,
I'M GONNA GO FIGURE OUT
HOW TO STOP THIS.
[drawer bangs shut]
NIKKI COLEMAN.
YOU DIDN'T MENTION THAT
OFFICER STARK MADE A CALL
TO YOUR RESIDENCE
EARLIER TODAY,
THAT YOU WERE ALSO
IN CHIEF MERRILL'S OFFICE.
AND NOW THEY'RE BOTH DEAD
THREE HOURS AFTER
THEY TALKED TO YOU.
- I--I WANNA HELP YOU,
BUT I CAN'T BE SEEN
TALKING TO YOU.
[knocks on door]
- AUDREY.
- CHRIS, NOT NOW.
- THEN I GUESS I WON'T
BOTHER YOU WITH THIS.
- HELLO AGAIN.
- HI.
- YOU TALKED TO NIKKI TOO?
- YEAH, SHE TALKED TO ME.
WHY?
SHE'S THE ONE?
BE A DOLL AND CLEAR THIS UP,
WILL YA?
DO THAT VOODOO
THAT YOU DO.
- I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
- YOU'RE THE ONE
THAT'S CAUSING THIS DISEASE,
SO JUST FIX IT,
WILL YOU?
- OKAY.
I HAVEN'T EVEN
TOLD HER YET.
- I'M DYING.
GIVE ME FIVE MINUTES
WITH PATIENT ZERO.
I'LL HAVE HER HEALING LEPERS.
LOOK AT HER.
SHE'S PRACTICALLY
IN LOVE WITH ME.
- WHAT HAS HAPPENED TO YOU?
YOU'VE COMPLETELY CHANGED.
- YEAH, WHATEVER.
I'M GOING TO THE HOSPITAL.
- NO, YOU CAN'T LEAVE, OKAY?
PEOPLE OUT THERE WILL SHOOT YOU.
- NOBODY WANTS TO SHOOT ME.
- REALLY?
YOU'RE A SCIENTIST.
TELL ME, WHAT WORKS FASTER--
YOUR TROUBLE OR A BULLET?
LISTEN, I CAN SAVE YOU
IF YOU JUST LET ME GET THROUGH
TO THIS VERY SCARED,
AND NOW, THANKS TO YOU,
VERY CONFUSED WOMAN.
ALL RIGHT?
JUST LET ME DO MY JOB.
- MAN, I WISH MY AFFLICTION
WORKED ON YOU.
- USUALLY A TROUBLE
LIKE YOURS
IS TRIGGERED
BY A TRAUMATIC EVENT.
DID SOMETHING LIKE THAT
HAPPEN RECENTLY?
PLEASE.
YOU CAN TELL ME.
- NO, LIKE, I--
YOU DON'T SEE--
I--I CAN'T SAY ANYTHING.
HE'S BACK.
AND HE'LL HURT ME AGAIN,
KILL ME EVEN.
- IS THAT WHY YOU
CALLED OFFICER STARK?
IS THAT WHY YOU CAME DOWN
TO THE STATION?
BECAUSE YOU'RE
BEING ABUSED?
OKAY, LISTEN, THAT MAN
THAT YOU'RE AFRAID OF,
HE CAN'T HURT YOU HERE,
ALL RIGHT?
YOU'RE SAFE.
- NO, I'M NEVER SAFE.
YOU DON'T UNDERSTAND. I--
IT TOOK ME YEARS.
I RAN AWAY.
I CHANGED MY NAME.
TODAY HE FOUND ME.
HE SAID IF I TALKED
TO THE POLICE
HE'LL KILL ME.
- [sighs]
UH, EXCUSE ME.
UM, HI.
I'M HUGH UNDERWOOD.
I'M A DOCTOR.
- YEAH, CHRIS BRODY.
I'D SHAKE YOUR HAND,
BUT I'M PRETTY MUCH DYING.
- AH, I'M SORRY,
CHRIS.
UM, I JUST SAW YOU IN THERE
WITH THE DETECTIVE
AND THAT,
UM, NIKKI WOMAN.
WHAT'S GOING ON?
- MY GIRLFRIEND,
OR WHATEVER SHE IS,
DOESN'T WANT ME
TO LEAVE.
SHE'S THE DETECTIVE.
SHE'S IN THERE
CHATTING UP A STORM
WHILE I'M OUT HERE
DYING.
- I MIGHT BE ABLE
TO HELP YOU.
IF I CAN GET YOU
TO THE HOSPITAL IN TIME,
I MIGHT BE ABLE
TO SAVE YOUR LIFE.
THE ONLY THING IS,
THERE'S NO WAY
THEY'RE GONNA LET US
OUT OF HERE OTHERWISE.
WE'RE GONNA NEED A GUN
OR SOMETHING.
- IT'S STAN, RIGHT?
- YEAH. THANKS
FOR REMEMBERING.
- YEAH.
UM, STAN, PARKER WANTED ME
TO GET THAT ENVELOPE
THAT YOU PUT
INTO EVIDENCE.
- SURE.
- I THINK THAT
ALL OF THOSE YEARS
THAT YOU SPENT
ABSORBING THAT ABUSE,
SWALLOWING THAT POISON,
I THINK TODAY
WHEN HE SHOWED UP
IT FINALLY LEAKED OUT.
IT'S BEEN INFECTING
ALL THESE PEOPLE.
LISTEN, IF YOU
TELL ME WHO HE IS,
WE CAN CONFRONT HIM,
AND MAYBE WE
CAN END THIS THING.
- HE'S--
HE KNOWS I'M HERE.
HE KNOWS
I'M TALKING TO YOU.
- NO. HOW WOULD HE KNOW THAT
UNLESS HE'S...
HERE.
- [gasps]
- EXCUSE ME, OFFICER.
MIND IF I HAVE
A WORD WITH MY WIFE?
- GET OVER THERE.
- ALL RIGHT, ALL RIGHT.
OKAY, YOU'RE IN CHARGE.
- YES, I AM.
I'VE HEARD ABOUT
THE FREAKS IN HAVEN.
BUT CREATING A PESTILENCE?
- YOU DON'T HAVE TO
DO THIS, HUGH.
- WELL, NOW I DO,
DON'T I?
BECAUSE SHE
COMPLAINED ABOUT ME.
- SHE DIDN'T DO
ANYTHING WRONG.
- [sobs]
- SHE DID DO
ONE THING RIGHT.
SHE GAVE EVERYONE ELSE
THE DISEASE EXCEPT ME,
AND NOW
THEY'RE ALL DYING.
MAYBE...
THAT'S BECAUSE...
YOU KNOW...
I'M THE ONLY ONE WHO
TRULY UNDERSTANDS YOU, HUH?
- HEY.
HUGH.
BUDDY.
LET'S TALK ABOUT THIS.
- SIT DOWN.
YOU'VE ALREADY DONE ENOUGH.
YOU ALREADY GAVE HIM MY GUN.
- HEY!
DON'T YOU TALK TO HIM
LIKE THAT.
MAYBE YOU NEED TO BE
TAUGHT A LITTLE RESPECT.
WHAT DO YOU THINK?
WAIT A SECOND.
HOW COME YOU'RE NOT SICK
LIKE THE OTHERS?
- NATHAN, COME ON.
YOU CAN'T JUST
LOCK ME IN HERE.
I'M NOT--I'M NOT
GONNA DO ANYTHING.
- YOU'RE NOT THINKING RIGHT.
- NATHAN, I GOT BACKUP.
THE SHERIFF'S TEN MINUTES OUT.
- GREAT.
- NOT GREAT.
OUR BUDDIES OUT HERE
MUST HAVE A SCANNER
AND HEARD
THE CALL GO OUT.
THEY'RE GEARING UP.
LOOKS LIKE THEY'RE COMING IN.
- THEY WANNA WIPE US OUT
BEFORE HELP GETS HERE.
- THEY'RE COMING IN THE BACK.
I'VE GOT YOU COVERED.
- NATHAN.
YOU GOTTA LET ME GO
WITH YOU.
- I'M NOT LETTING YOU
GET YOURSELF KILLED.
- NATHAN!
WAIT!
NATHAN,
DON'T DO THIS TO ME!
- I'M SORRY.
I CAN'T LET YOU LIVE.
YOU'LL KEEP ME AWAY
FROM MY NICOLE.
- HEY, COME ON, DOC.
I GET YOU.
I UNDERSTAND WHY
YOU'RE DOING THIS.
SOMETIMES IT'S...
- ISOLATING YOURSELF,
FEELING WEAK,
THAT'S WHAT CAUSED THIS.
BUT WHAT YOU
HAVE INSIDE OF YOU NOW,
YOU NEED
TO TURN IT AROUND.
FIGHT BACK, NIKKI.
- I CAN'T.
- YOU DON'T WANNA
SEE ME DIE, DO YA?
- LISTEN, YOU'RE NOT
JUST HURTING YOURSELF.
YOU'RE HURTING EVERYONE
ELSE HERE, OKAY?
- [sighs]
- FIND THE STRENGTH
AND FIGHT BACK.
- ALL RIGHT,
THAT'S ENOUGH OUT OF YOU!
- STOP IT, HUGH!
NO MORE.
- WHAT DID YOU SAY?
- YOU HEARD ME.
[sighs deeply]
- NOW, I'M GONNA
COUNT TO THREE,
AND YOU ARE GONNA
GET ON YOUR KNEES
AND APOLOGIZE.
- NO.
YOU HAVE POISONED ME
WITH YOUR ABUSE
FOR YEARS.
I'M DONE.
SO KILL ME
IF YOU WANT.
BUT I DON'T THINK
YOU WILL,
BECAUSE YOU'RE NOTHING
BUT A COWARD.
ROT IN HELL.
- [groaning]
[gasping]
- [breathes heavily]
I...
I--I DID THAT
TO HIM.
I--I KILLED HIM.
- NO.
LISTEN, YOU SAVED US.
HEY, IT'S OVER.
- NOT FOR THOSE GUYS
OUTSIDE.
THEY'RE COMING IN.
- WHY?
- WIPE OUT THE CURSE
AND EVERYONE ELSE.
- OKAY.
WELL, GO STOP 'EM.
I'LL CALL FOR BACKUP.
- DWIGHT, DO YOU COPY?
[gun cocks]
- THEY'RE COMING.
GET BACK.
[gunfire]
[siren wailing]
- LET'S GET OUT OF HERE!
[car door slams shut,
tires screech]
[siren wailing]
- [breathes heavily]
- DWIGHT, YOU'RE SHOT.
- ONE GRAZED MY NECK.
LET ME GUESS--
YOU DIDN'T CATCH
A SINGLE BULLET.
- NOTHING HIT THE WALLS.
I'M NOT HIT.
I DON'T GET IT.
- BULLETS--THEY,
UH, TEND TO FIND ME.
IT'S A LONG STORY.
- BULLETS TEND
TO FIND YOU?
THAT'S YOUR TROUBLE?
WELL, YOU WERE RIGHT.
THE WAY THINGS ARE GOING,
I MIGHT NEED YOU AROUND
MORE THAN EVER.
- I'M SORRY FOR YOUR LOSS,
MR. CROCKER.
I TRULY AM.
- SHE DIDN'T KNOW ANYTHING
ABOUT THIS TOWN.
- SHE WAS ONE OF
THE MANY INNOCENT VICTIMS
OF THE TROUBLED.
I LOST MY WIFE
TO THEM TOO.
- I DON'T UNDERSTAND
ANY OF THIS.
- I CAN HELP YOU,
MR. CROCKER.
BUT YOU'RE GONNA HAVE
TO PROVE TO ME
THAT YOU'RE WORTHY.
- REVEREND.
THANK YOU.
- I'LL PRAY FOR HER.
- DWIGHT, I NEED YOU
TO DO SOMETHING FOR ME.
EVI RYAN--MAKE IT
LOOK LIKE A SUICIDE
OR AN ACCIDENT,
JUST AS LONG AS
THE CASE IS CLOSED.
- WE'RE NOT TALKING
ABOUT COVERING UP
A SUPERNATURAL EVENT.
THIS IS A MURDER.
- WE CAN'T INVESTIGATE THIS
WITH THE STATE POLICE
LOOKING OVER OUR SHOULDER.
- EVI WAS SHOT
IN THE CHEST.
SHE HAS BLACK VEINS
IN HER ARMS.
THE MEDICAL EXAMINER'S NEVER--
- NO PROBLEM.
WOULDN'T BE THE TOUGHEST THING
I EVER HAD TO DO.
IF IT'S OKAY
WITH YOU, CHIEF.
- DO IT.
ONE MORE THING--
WE GOT CHIEF MERRILL'S
CELL PHONE LOGS.
GUESS WHO HE TALKED
TO HALF A DOZEN TIMES
DURING THE LOCKDOWN?
- THE REV.
HE'S IN THE MIDDLE
OF ALL OF THIS.
SORRY. I GOT CAUGHT UP
AT WORK, SO...
- LET ME GO FIRST, OKAY?
[sighs]
I SCREWED UP.
HUGELY.
AND GIVING YOUR GUN
TO A PSYCHOPATH...
THAT MAY HAVE BEEN
THE LEAST OF MY MISTAKES.
I LOST YOUR TRUST.
I THOUGHT I COULD HANDLE
MY AFFLICTION.
- CHRIS, YOU--
- LAST NIGHT...
I GAVE INTO IT...
AND NEARLY
GOT PEOPLE KILLED.
AND THAT THING
I SAID TO YOU ABOUT
WISHING YOU
WEREN'T IMMUNE...
THAT'S NOT TRUE.
I WANNA BE WITH YOU, AUDREY.
I NEED TO BE WITH YOU.
- YOU ONCE TOLD ME,
"I WANT YOU
BECAUSE YOU'RE YOU."
WANTING ME AND NEEDING ME,
THEY'RE TWO DIFFERENT THINGS.
I CAN'T BE THE PERSON
THAT KEEPS YOU YOU.
YOU GOTTA DO THAT
ON YOUR OWN.
- YEAH.
- IT'S JUST YOU'D--
YOU'D EVENTUALLY START
RESENTING ME FOR IT.
- I THINK THE BEST THING
FOR ME TO DO
IS TO JUST...GO
SOMEWHERE BY MYSELF,
AWAY FROM OTHER PEOPLE.
- NO, CHRIS, THAT'S NOT
WHAT I'M SAYING.
- YOU KNOW, SOMEDAY
THE TROUBLES ARE GONNA END,
AND I'M GONNA GO BACK
TO BEING THE GUY
THAT EVERYBODY HATES.
MAYBE THEN I'LL BE A GUY
THAT YOU CAN LOVE.
Captioning by CaptionMax
www.captionmax.com
- &l DON'T YOU SEE &l
&l I'M THE ONE
FOR YOU &l
&l YOU'RE
THE ONE FOR ME &l
&l DON'T YOU SEE &l
&l THE LOVE I GOT &l
&l IS THE LOVE
YOU NEED &l
&l DON'T YOU SEE &l
&l I'M ALL DRESSED UP &l
&l TO BE WHAT YOU
WANT ME TO BE &l
&l I'M ALL DRESSED UP,
ALL DRESSED UP &l
&l ALL DRESSED UP &l